<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <link>https://tjmt.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Introduction</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tjmt.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Mental Health Surge Model</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/projects/surge_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/projects/surge_model/</guid>
      <description>The Stategy Unit were commissioned by Mersey Care NHS FT to create a model to estimate the surge in demand to Mental Health services caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. Based on published evidence, SUS datasets (MHSDS, IAPT), and expert opinion we produced a System&amp;rsquo;s Dynamic&amp;rsquo;s Model in R. This model was then given a web user interface so people could interact with the model.
The code is released under an MIT license and is available on the SU GitHub, and the model is available to use here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NHS-R Conference 2021</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/projects/nhsr_conf21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/projects/nhsr_conf21/</guid>
      <description>For the 2021 NHS-R conference I delivered a workshop on functional programming (slides, video) and a lightning talk on Object Orientated Programming in R using S3 (slides, video).
I also had the pleasure of helping out in two other workshops: &amp;ldquo;Reproducible computation at scale in R with {targets}&amp;rdquo; by Will Landau and an introduction to &amp;ldquo;Artificial Neural Networks in R with Keras and TensorFlow&amp;rdquo; by Leon Eyrich Jessen. Both of these sessions were fantastically informative and delivered expertly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{NHSRplotthedots}</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/projects/nhsr_ptd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/projects/nhsr_ptd/</guid>
      <description>A number of individuals from the NHS-R community (Simon, Chris R, Chris M, Tom S, Zoe, and myself) collaborated to build an R package to implement the &amp;ldquo;Making Data Count&amp;rdquo; SPC rules and charts. The goal was to replicate the functionality provided in their excel tool.
We have just reached version 0.1.0 and published the package to CRAN. You can install it yourself by running
install.packages(&amp;#34;NHSRplotthedots&amp;#34;) The documentation for the package is available here, and you can view the code on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we should use UUIDs for all primary keys</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/blog/20211130-uuid_primary_keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/blog/20211130-uuid_primary_keys/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with HES data on a project, and the current structure of tables we have is for each of the different datasets (Inpatients, Outpatients, Emeregency Care, etc.) we have a separate table for each financial year. Within these there will be a column like EPIKEY or ATTENDKEY which is the primary key in that table. This key is stored as a BIGINT.
This key restarts counting each year&amp;hellip; well, sort of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions for R</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/blog/20211111-github_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/blog/20211111-github_actions/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Actions is a super useful way to automate some of the boring tasks that we have to do day in, day out. And the wonderful r-lib have created a bunch of actions for R that will make your life super easy. Along with the {usethis} package, and the function usethis::use_github_action(), you can easily set up a bunch of predefined actions.
Below is an example of an action that I created for my talks repository recently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
