<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <link>https://tjmt.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Introduction</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tjmt.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Mental Health Surge Model</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/projects/surge_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/projects/surge_model/</guid>
      <description>The Stategy Unit were commissioned by Mersey Care NHS FT to create a model to estimate the surge in demand to Mental Health services caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. Based on published evidence, SUS datasets (MHSDS, IAPT), and expert opinion we produced a System&amp;rsquo;s Dynamic&amp;rsquo;s Model in R. This model was then given a web user interface so people could interact with the model.
The code is released under an MIT license and is available on the SU GitHub, and the model is available to use here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{NHSRplotthedots}</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/projects/nhsr_ptd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/projects/nhsr_ptd/</guid>
      <description>A number of individuals from the NHS-R community (Simon, Chris R, Chris M, Tom S, Zoe, and myself) collaborated to build an R package to implement the &amp;ldquo;Making Data Count&amp;rdquo; SPC rules and charts. The goal was to replicate the functionality provided in their excel tool.
We have just reached version 0.1.0 and published the package to CRAN. You can install it yourself by running
install.packages(&amp;#34;NHSRplotthedots&amp;#34;) The documentation for the package is available here, and you can view the code on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions for R</title>
      <link>https://tjmt.uk/blog/20211111-github_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjmt.uk/blog/20211111-github_actions/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Actions is a super useful way to automate some of the boring tasks that we have to do day in, day out. And the wonderful r-lib have created a bunch of actions for R that will make your life super easy. Along with the {usethis} package, and the function usethis::use_github_action(), you can easily set up a bunch of predefined actions.
Below is an example of an action that I created for my talks repository recently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
